<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://governance.foundation/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://governance.foundation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-22T00:07:12+00:00</updated><id>https://governance.foundation/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Governance Foundation</title><subtitle>Governance Foundation exploring foundations for governance</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Governance Experience Platform</title><link href="https://governance.foundation/blog/2020/07/15/governance-experience-platform" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Governance Experience Platform" /><published>2020-07-14T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-14T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://governance.foundation/blog/2020/07/15/governance-experience-platform</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://governance.foundation/blog/2020/07/15/governance-experience-platform">&lt;div class=&quot;sticky&quot;&gt;
    &lt;aside class=&quot;sidebar__right&quot;&gt;
&lt;nav class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
      &lt;header&gt;&lt;h4 class=&quot;nav__title&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fas fa-file-alt&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; On This Page&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;toc__menu&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pathology-of-organisational-miscommunication&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-pathology-of-organisational-miscommunication&quot;&gt;Pathology of Organisational Miscommunication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sharing-knowledge-in-socio-technical-organisations&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-sharing-knowledge-in-socio-technical-organisations&quot;&gt;Sharing Knowledge in Socio-Technical Organisations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#organisational-deafness&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-organisational-deafness&quot;&gt;Organisational Deafness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#governance-reborn&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-governance-reborn&quot;&gt;Governance Reborn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#beyond-governance&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-beyond-governance&quot;&gt;Beyond Governance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
.page__hero--overlay p, .page__hero--overlay h1{
    background-color: rgba(240, 87, 66, 0.8);
    max-width: fit-content !important;
    border-radius: 25px;
    padding: 10px;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a clear need for a new way to help to govern organisations. This need is apparent from the continual search for efficiencies and effectiveness of organisations which demonstrated through transformations and a smorgasbord of frameworks available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing patterns and frameworks focus on educating individual parts of the organisation in order to mature the organisation as a whole. Primarily this education efforts usually occur at a point in time where an organisation needs a boost to mature past current state. These education efforts are an oversight approach when applied and practised produces the desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally all organisations are socio-technical entities and at their very nature are very complicated at best. Maturing organisations is a process for developing the social and technical layers; this requires architecting and communicating of change across the organisation and its where the challenges start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pathology-of-organisational-miscommunication&quot;&gt;Pathology of Organisational Miscommunication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In organisations miscommunication is pathological, and it is prevalent in all types of socio-technical organisations startups, government and corporates. The primary reason for this is audience conflict, where teams loyalty at lower levels often erode its ability to deal with external ideas, other groups and its allegiance to the organisation as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These organisational communication issues further amplified by scale and velocity at which an organisation tries to move. In an organisation, geographic, corporate, and domain silos provide a ground on which miscommunication impeds communication and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socio-technical organisations need to promote empathy in an organisation that allows teams to respect each other’s contributions as well as maintain the shared purpose of organisational goal. Organisations that enable teams to embrace the shared language and establish mutual regard towards other groups would develop organisational cohesion that will further reinforce organisational success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significant social issues in organisations that impact performance fall into the following categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communication - ability to communicate effectively without translation errors, without shared data and language this becomes impossible and impacts collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collaboration - the ability to share resources, teams ability to share their resources and allow other teams contribution impacts cooperation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooperation - ability to help each other, teams abilities to provide support to other groups when required by teams impacts coordination.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coordination - ability to coordinate the effort across teams and time in pursuit of organisational goals depend on teams in that organisation to be able to communicate, collaborate and cooperate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the approaches to deal with social issues is to encourage cohesion across teams. For organisations to establish organisational cohesion, all participants need to feel that their contribution is valuable and equally important. Enabling valuable contribution can be achieved by providing tailored experience at the team level, in turn, enabling teams to achieve their goals while ensuring that all groups are working off the same shared knowledge. Establishing a shared knowledge base and providing tailored experiences for groups creates a common purpose, facilitates communication and enables cooperation, all of this enabling coordination across the organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sharing-knowledge-in-socio-technical-organisations&quot;&gt;Sharing Knowledge in Socio-Technical Organisations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organisations are socio-technical platforms that attempt to facilitate socially driven change to technical systems created by the evolution of that organisation. Coordinating social change has become difficult to achieve without shared knowledge, that can be adopted and tailored though experiences for individuals that make up those organisations. By doing this, organisations will provide a method that will ensure that everyone involved feels that their contribution is valued and is equally important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Establishing a shared knowledge that whole organisation use as a base for decisions requires a new type of governance platform. A new governance platform that will provide a foundation for defining governance models so that they can be leveraged by AI to provide direction and insights while maintaining human social participation. This platform will provide a central core to each organisation and will support all interactions across organisations and will enable orchestration of organisational systems and will enhance social participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;organisational-deafness&quot;&gt;Organisational Deafness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organisational complexity creates a paradox of organisational deafness, where the sheer amount of noise drowns individual ability to get a message heard, let alone have that message make an impact. This primarily because organisations are unable to listen and engage with all inputs to that organisation. This further eventuates the paradox leads to organisations to adopt the path of less resistance approach though out its delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forces that bring about change to an organisation are both external and internal. External forces bring about changes that an organisation is unable to control, and it relies on its social ecosystem to predict and counter all external effects. Organisational internal social ecosystem translates external input and converts these into internalising actions that adjust organisational structures—the more efficient this process, the more effective the organisation as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organisations internal social ecosystem efficiency is coupled with the effectiveness of that organisation; therefore, organisations that focus on the health of their social ecosystem would see positive outcomes for the organisation as a whole. The ability of an organisational social ecosystem to actively listen and synchronise changes needed to the organisation is largely rendered impractical due to the complexity of organisations. This leaves a minority of inputs that are leveraged for establishing a direction for change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability of an organisation to actively listen and act on all inputs would provide a method to synchronise changes need to achieve effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;governance-reborn&quot;&gt;Governance Reborn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The case for a new governance platform is all too apparent across all industries and social divides. Oldways of doing things within organisations cannot keep up with breadth, depth and scale of new age demands. The complexity of organisational dependencies, social ways of working and technology ecosystems create a foundation for unpredictable delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governance Experience Platform (GXP) is a platform that enables the development of Organisational Experiences that leverage foundational knowledge and structures that self-reinforces its foundations. GXP is a platform that will provide the foundations on which organisations can create organisational experiences that harness the shared knowledge into a shared data structure that further reinforce organisations foundations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organisations need to be able to create experiences that are efficient, effective and personalised to an individual level, crossing domain, organisational and geographic boundaries. GXP focus is to provide a foundation for creating experiences that facilitate social and procedural governance patterns, that can demonstrate and elevate the contribution of each individual to the social organisation journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beyond-governance&quot;&gt;Beyond Governance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanity needs a way to share governance models from small businesses and communities to conglomerates and countries. Current methods of sharing governance models rest on ad hoc consumer-driven approach. The breadth of governance landscape prevents correlation between governance models at any level. GXP will provide a mechanism to share organisational experiences across boundaries without compromising shared knowledge of those organisations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GXP will enable organisational governance and provide a pathway to establish trusted relationships with governments that provide stewardship in shared societal responsibilities with organisations. Establishing a non-invasive pathway for governments to contribute to organisational governance would facilitate cohesion between organisations without removing the free-market competition fundamentals that drive economies where those organisations operate.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Barrass</name><email>me@maxbarrass.com</email><uri>http://maxbarrass.com</uri></author><category term="blog" /><category term="governance" /><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">A case for a new governance platfrom that caters to individual experiences.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A case for Governance Framework</title><link href="https://governance.foundation/blog/2020/07/15/a-case-for-governance-foundation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A case for Governance Framework" /><published>2020-07-03T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-03T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://governance.foundation/blog/2020/07/15/a-case-for-governance-foundation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://governance.foundation/blog/2020/07/15/a-case-for-governance-foundation">&lt;h2 id=&quot;copy-paste-governance&quot;&gt;Copy-Paste Governance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy-paste governance approach does not work. This approach refers to an attempt to replicate the governance approach from one context to another. In the organisational context, this means copying/mimicking a governance pattern of another organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organisational governance patterns are evolutionary; they are outcomes of micro transformations performed by the organisation over numbers of years. They are representative of the social and technical structures as well as the evolution journey of that organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organisational governance is the historical record of the organisation evolution; it a combination of persistence and maturity of each part of the organisation over time. Thus simply copying governance pattern of an organisation in time to another organisation does not produce the same results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organisations are complex socio-technical organisms, and applying externally conceived governance patterns would mean that all of the parts that make up organisation would need to go through a transformation on a maturity curve that was followed by the organisation from which governance pattern being copied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-case-for-governance-foundation&quot;&gt;A case for Governance Foundation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across all industries, organisations use oversight as the primary method of leadership and stewardship, and this approach is well defined by oversight governance. In summary oversight governance means that all of the corrective actions are applied post specific events; it’s a reactive command and control approach. This approach works when the central command has ample experience to deal with issues as they arise. When things get too complicated, this approach leads to failure, in best cases, adding to the command experience and allowing a clean to restart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across all industries, the old way of helping organisations mature is not scaling; this is primarily due to the level of complexity that has evolved in social and technical layers of organisations. Tried and tested societal patterns for managing change are tested as socio-technical complexity increases. Existing models are complex and primarily used as an oversight stewardship approach, usually as a reaction to the organisation in need of help. The situation further complicated by barriers for knowledge sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better approach would be to provide a governance foundation as a form of a scaffold for new organisations so that as they evolve, they unlock and leverage parts of the framework that matches their maturity. This approach would provide a mechanism that would minimise routine transformations that are influence organisations of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, this approach would provide a method of sharing and leveraging knowledge across organisations, as well as provide a central holistic knowledge area for contributors to focus their attention without creating unnecessary deviations. At the same time providing a platform for sharing patterns and maintaining the visibility of contribution by the authors.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Barrass</name><email>me@maxbarrass.com</email><uri>http://maxbarrass.com</uri></author><category term="blog" /><category term="governance" /><category term="blog" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Governance Foundation</title><link href="https://governance.foundation/blog/2020/06/16/governance-foundation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Governance Foundation" /><published>2020-06-15T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-15T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://governance.foundation/blog/2020/06/16/governance-foundation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://governance.foundation/blog/2020/06/16/governance-foundation">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Governance Foundation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site will aim to collate relevant knowledge that provides a foundation for developing governance frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as providing insight on available governance frameworks, a new concept’s for governance will be explored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the journey!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Max Barrass</name><email>me@maxbarrass.com</email><uri>http://maxbarrass.com</uri></author><category term="blog" /><category term="governance" /><category term="blog" /></entry></feed>